Zenan Li

San Jose, CA | (714)-326-3173 | zenanlicareer@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/chrislizenan/ https://lizenan.github.io/ https://github.com/lizenan

ABOUT ME

I'm a Research and development engineer at Deepmotion with 5+ years experience. I obtained my M.S. Degree supervised by <u>Prof. Mikhail Gofman</u> at California State University, Fullerton and then I was supervised by <u>Prof. Libin Liu</u> for 2 years at Deepmotion.

My Research interests focus on Generative AI, Computer Vision, Model Optimization for Real-Time, Data Processing. My biggest passion is commercializing ML research models/topics to impact different industries.

RESEARCH INTERESTS

Generative AI RAG, Character Motion as		RAG, Character Motion and Video Generation with Multimodalities,
		Multimodal Retrieval, MLLM, Video Understanding
•	Computer Vision	Human Body/Face/Hand Pose Estimation, Multiple Object Tracking
	_	Object Detection/Segmentation, 3D Lifting
•	Model Optimization	Real-Time on-device, Transfer Learing, Distillation Learning, Software/Hardware
	-	Acceleration
•	Data Processing	Cross-modality Data Synthesis, Data Augmentation, Model Interpretability
		and Intermediate Feature Editing

EXPERIENCES

Research&Development Engineer	Nov 2021-Present
DeepMotion, Inc. San Mateo, CA	
Associate R&D Engineer	Aug 2019-Nov 2021
DeepMotion, Inc. San Mateo, CA	
Machine Learning Intern	May 2018-Jul 2019
Beneufit Inc. Palo Alto, CA	
Research Assistant	Sep 2018-Jul 2019
California State University, Fullerton. Fullerton, CA	
Full Stack Engineer	Apr 2016-Jul 2017
China Telecom Co. Ltd. Guangzhou, China	

PROJECTS

• SayMotion

Nov 2022-Present
SayMotion is a generative AI Cloud/API service that employs a combination of Causal Transformer models,
Mask Transformers, and VQVAE as its core architectural components, generate motion via Multimodal

Conditioning. The product is designed to address the challenges in text/motion to motion generation/editing by integrating various multi-modal models to perform training data synthesis and augmentation which achieved 0.8M data size. In the post-processing stage, SayMotion incorporates a range of methods to refine the generated outputs. Specifically, it utilizes LLM+RAG for prompt optimization, various auxiliary models(e.g. Text-Motion-Retrieval, Motion Discriminator) are applied for output motion selections. Accepted to SIGGRAPH'24 real-time live.

Animate 3D Aug 2019-Present Animate 3D is a cutting-edge machine learning Cloud/API/SDK service designed to accurately motion capture human body, hand, and facial poses in RGB video streams. optimized for both real-time performance and high precision. Capable of processing multiple individuals simultaneously, this system integrates advanced techniques in object detection, object tracking, pose estimation, person re-identification (ReID), and segmentation(e.g. Segment Anything). Score-Guided Diffusion method is applied for post-processing. Featured demo in Snapdragon Tech Summit 2021 Keynote, US Patent granted.

Tracer

May 2018-July 2019

Tracer is an advanced clinical application designed to diagnose movement disorders by analyzing joint movements through time-series pose estimation. The system is trained on extensive clinical data, allowing it to identify subtle patterns and anomalies in motor function that may indicate the presence of a movement disorder.

US Patent granted.

Face and Ear Dual-modality Identification

Sep 2018-Jul 2019
Face and Ear Dual-modality Identification is an advanced approach to human identification that leverages

Convolutional Neural Networks (CNNs) to jointly encode features from both facial and ear images. By integrating these two modalities, the system aims to improve identification accuracy. Few-shot learning and transfer learning are applied to address the face, ear data imbalance.

• Multiple-Person 3D Human Mesh Recovery from Single 2D Picture Oct 2018-May 2019 Generate multiple SMPL poses all at once and end-to-end by leveraging Densepose's intermediate features.

• Early Research projects

iMaterialist Challenge (Fashion) at FGVC5, Car Plate Recognition, Stock Price Predictor, Monkey Species Classification, etc.

SKILLS

• Languages Python, C++, Java, Javascript, C#, SQL, CSS, HTML

• Frameworks/Libraries Pytorch, OpenCV, PEFT, Transformers--Hugging face, Tensorboard, Scikit-image,

Matplotlib, SciPy, Onnx, TensorRT, CUDA, cuDNN, TensorFlow Lite, TensorFlow,

Keras, Scikit-learn, Pandas, Spacy, NLTK, Apex, Pytorch Lighting

• **Deployment Apps** Docker, Nginx, Apache

Cloud Services GCP, AWS, Lambda Labs, GoDaddy

Version Control System Git, SVN
 3D Tools Maya, Unity
 Project Management Jira, Linear

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Computer Science Aug 2017-May 2019

California State University, Fullerton

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science Sep 2012-Jul 2016

North China University of Science and Technology

Exchange Program, Computer Science Jan 2015-Jan 2016

California State University, Fullerton

PATENTS&PUBLICATIONS

Enhancing Narratives with SayMotion's text-to-3D animation and LLMs.
 Kevin He, Annette Lapham, and Zenan Li
 [SIGGRAPH'24 | Project | Paper]

- Methods and systems for detecting 3d poses from 2d images and editing 3d poses
 Kaichuan He, Jakub Stepien, Zenan Li, Grzegorz Kabza, Marcin Hulist, Mikolaj Korcz [US Patent'24 | Project | Paper]
- Measuring dynamic body movement
 Jeffery Broderick, Douglas Van Blaricom, Jerome Lisk, Zenan Li, Sukhad Anand
 [US Patent'22 | Project | Paper]
- Multiple-Person 3D Human Mesh Recovery from Single 2D Picture

Zenan Li

[Thesis'19 | Project | Paper]

EVENTS

• Silicon Valley Chinese AI Forum Multimodal Panel Discussion

Presenter: Kevin He, Contributor: Zenan Li

- Game Developers Conference(GDC) 2024 Exhibitor
- Game Developers Conference(GDC) 2023 Exhibitor
- CVPR 2023 Attendees